NEW YORK STATE CONFERENCE OF LOCAL MENTAL HYGIENE DIRECTORS RECORDS (APAP315) 1950-2009
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
- Newsletters, 1980-2008; Undated; 8; 0.6 cu. ft.
  - January-February, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Spring and October-December, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - January-December, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Conference updates from chair, spring edition, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - January-December, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - January-December, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - January-December, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - January-December, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - January-December, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - January-December, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Undated newsletters (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Reports and Publications, 1982; 1989-2006; Undated; 9; 2.6 cu. ft.
  This series consists of various reports and booklets that were used by the NYSCLMHD in the course of business, but were not always produced by the Conference. They are from organizations such as the New York State legislature, the Office of Mental Health, the Office of Alcoholism and Substance Abuse, the state prison system, and the Conference of Local Mental Hygiene Directors themselves. Topics range from mental healthcare in the twenty-first century, to juvenile mental health, to criminal offenders with mental illness.
  - 2000 Network Performance Measures, 2003 March (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - AIDS: The Epidemic That Won't Wait, 1989 June (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Alcoholism and Substance Abuse Condolidation Report, 1992 January (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Assessing the Nature and Prevalence of the Mentally Ill in Suffolk County's Criminal Justice System, 2000 March (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - At the Crossroads: Realigning future services, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - At the Crossroads: Expanding Community-Based Care for Children and Families, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Beyond Awareness: A Campaign to Reduce the Stigma of Mental Illness, 2002 February (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Blueprint for Change: Research and Child Adolescent Mental Health, 2001 May (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Commission on the Community Mental Health System for the 21st Century Final Reports, 1999 April (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Community Mental Health System for the 21st Century: Critical Planning, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Confronting the Disaster: Restructuring personal support services for New York's high risk and troubled children, 1991 March (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "The Courage to Change": Guide, integrating services for co-occurring disorders in justice system, 1999 December (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Criminalizing the Seriously Mentally Ill: The Abuse of Jails as Mental Hospitals, 1993 April (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Crossing the Line from Empowerment to Neglect: The Case of Project L.I.F.E., 1994 July (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Draft: Behavioral Outcomes-"It's Not Just Academic", Faulkner and Gray, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Dual Diagnosis: Mental Health/Mental Retardation, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Final Report of the Temporary Implementation Council on Consolidation, 1994 June (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Forensic Mental Health: Final Report, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Future of Child Welfare Funding: Rebuilding the Partnership, 1998 October (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Gains Institute newsletters, 1999-2001 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Governor's draft legislation on authorized involuntary mental hygiene and social services- Conference response and financial report, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Guide to Understanding Supports and Services, 2006 April (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Integrated Systems of Care for Children's Mental Health: Final report, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Integrated Systems of Care for Children's Mental Health: Technical Assistance Resource Book, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Integrating services for co-occurring disorders, draft, 2000 February (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Integrating services for co-occurring disorders, 2000 March (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Interim report to the legislature on state-operated alcoholism treatment centers, 1994 December (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Jail Mental Health Services in New York State- planning workshop, Lake Placid, Undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Jail Mental Health Services in New York State- planning workshop, Kingston, Undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Jail Mental Health Services in New York State- planning workshop, Syracuse, Undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Keeping track of New York City's children: A citizen's committee status report, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - KPMG public services presentation, 2001 June (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Legislative status sheet, 1994 May (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Local Stewardship and the Commission on the 21st Century- draft, Undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Mandated Mental Health Insurance in New York State: A Research Report, 1990 April (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Mediation Mental Health: Alliance Dispute Resolution, 1994 July (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Mental Health Funding: Final Report, 1999 April (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Mental Health Issues in the Workplace: How the Americans with Disabilities Act Protects You Against Employment Discrimination, 2000 June (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Mental Health Resource Handbook for Human Service Personnel, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Mental Hygiene Agencies Need to Develop a Better Working Relationship with Local Governments: Comptroller's report, 1993 March (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Mental Hygiene System: "A Dialogue for Change", 1982 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - MICA Program Directory: Treating and Supporting Persons with Coexisting Alcohol/Drug and Mental Health Disorders, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Mobilization for Our Children: Medicaid and Children's Mental Health, 1994 December (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Mobilization for Our Children: Restructuring Services for New York's High-Risk and Troubled Children, 1995 January (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - New York State Association of Counties Adopted Resolutions, 1992 March (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - New York State Commission on Quality Care for the Mentally Disabled, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - New York State Commission on Quality Care for the Mentally Disabled, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - New York State Comprehensive Housing Affordability Strategy (CHAS), 1994-1998 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - New York State Correctional Alternatives, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - New York State Counties: Their Beginnings, 1982 June (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - New York State Department of Mental Hygiene: Consolidated Fiscal Reporting Manual, 1990 June-1990 December (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - New York State Directory, Adolescent Alcohol and Substance Abuse Providers, 2002 March (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - New York State Managed Care Plan, 1991 October (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - New York State Office of Mental Health: Rights of Outpatients, Undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - New York State Performance Report for the Comprehensive Housing Affordability Strategy, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - New York State Practice Improvement Collaborative: New York's Science-to-Service Program, Undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - New York State Touchstones/Kids Count Data Book, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - New York State Touchstones/Kids Count Data Book, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - NYS Division of Probation and Correctional Alternatives……. Defendants and Offenders with Mental Illness, 2002 April (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - NYS Office of Alcoholism and Substance Abuse Services-- Shared Vision: The Future of State and County Collaborations, 2002 March (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - OASAS: Certification Process, Conference of Local Mental Hygiene Directors, 2002 May (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - OASAS: Five-Year Comprehensive Plan for Alcoholism and Substance Abuse Services, 1994-1999 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - OASAS: Substance Abuse Treatment for Persons in the Criminal Justice System, 2001 March (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Office of Mental Health: Outcome Measures for Outpatient Clinic Programs, 1993 June (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - OMRD Services for Eligible Individuals Involved in the Criminal Justice System, Undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Outpatient Mental Health Services, 1989 July (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Plan for the Consolidation of Harlem Valley and Hudson River Psychiatric Center, 1993 January (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Planning for the Future of Community Support Programs in New York State, 1994 June (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Qualitative Study of the Perceptions of the Meaning of Self-Help….., Undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Reforming the Delivery of Children's Services, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Regional Facility Capital Summaries, 1992 December (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Resource Directory: Comprehensive Community Mental Health Services for Children and Their Families, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Restraint-Seclusion Practices in New York State Psychiatric Facilities, 1994 September (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Salary Survey of Executive, Legislative, and Administrative Positions in New York State Counties, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Services for a Shared Population: Defendants and Offenders with Mental Illness, Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Serving the MR/DD Population: County Perspectives of Service Needs and Best Practices, 2002 December (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Speak: Suicide Prevention Education Awareness Kit, 2004 May (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - State Office of New York, Office of Mental Retardation and Developmental Disabilities, Report on major legislation, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - State of New York Commission on Quality Care for the Mentally Disabled: Safeguarding Public Funds, 1995 January (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Statewide Chartbook of Mental Health Information, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Statewide Comprehension Plan for Mental Health Services, 1993-1997 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Survey of Access to New York State Courts for Individuals with Disabilities, 1994 February (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Survey of Behavioral Healthcare Providers, 2002 October (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Table of contents to legislative bill packet on mental health concerns, 1994 August (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - TA Brief: Technical Assistance Center, Vol. 2, #1, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Treating Co-Occurring Mental Health and Addictive Disorders in New York State: A Comprehensive View, 2001 May (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Untangle the Web: Delivering Municipal Services Through the Internet, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Voices from the Front Line: Patients' Perspectives of Restraint and Seclusion Use, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - We Can Work Campaign: Employment Tool for People with Psychiatric Disabilities in New York State, Undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Willowbrook, From Institution to the Community, 1982 August (Box 4, Folder 9)